{"tossups": [{"question": "After this man has a panic attack at Madison Square Garden, he is taken to Yankee Stadium, where he recounts his guilt over his war-veteran brother's death from drunk driving. A character played by Busta Rhymes gives this man an envelope after this man's friend misses two free throws to lose the state basketball championship. A lawyer played by Matt Damon reveals this character's dying request in a  lm that ends with Israel Kamakawiwo'ole's (kah-MAH-kah-VEE-voh-OH-lay's) ukulele version of \"Somewhere over the Rainbow\" playing over the credits. This author of Avalon Landing yells \"punch the keys, for god sake!\" at a character sitting at a typewriter before maniacally screaming, \"Yes! Yes! You're the man now, dog!\" For 10 points, what reclusive author played by Sean Connery mentors a black teenager in a movie titled for \"finding\" him?", "answer": "William Forrester [accept either underlined portion; accept Finding Forrester]", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>William Forrester</u></b> [accept <b><u>either underlined portion</u></b>; accept <b><u>Finding Forrester</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["William Forrester", "William Forrester", "either underlined portion", "Finding Forrester"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "During World War I, Hog Island became the largest center for this industry in the world. Dwight Eisenhower called Andrew Higgins, a leader of this industry, \"the man who won the war.\" A center for this industry in Richmond, California, was the site of the  first Permanente Foundation hospital. Henry Kaiser used prefabrication and assembly-line methods to achieve enormous productivity in this industry. During World War II, this industry mass-produced products using steel that embrittled at low temperatures, causing some of those products to literally snap in half; the \"Victory\" model produced by this industry improved on the design flaws of those \"Liberty\" products. For 10 points, what industry produced destroyers and aircraft carriers during World War II?", "answer": "shipbuilding [accept equivalents mentioning the manufacture of ships or boats or other equivalents]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>shipbuilding</u></b> [accept <b><u>equivalents mentioning the manufacture of ships</u></b> or <b><u>boats</u></b> or other equivalents]", "acceptable": ["shipbuilding", "shipbuilding", "equivalents mentioning the manufacture of ships", "boats"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "G\u00c2\u00b7P\u00c2\u00b7C\u00c2\u00b7Rs sensitive to this compound are agonized by quisqualic (kwis-KWAH-lik) acid and have a conserved Venus &amp;ytrap domain. On industrial scale, amino acids are made by a Coryne\u00c2\u00b7bacterium (cor-\"EYE\"-nee-bacterium) named for this compound. Astrocytes overexpress importers for this compound, called E\u00c2\u00b7A\u00c2\u00b7A\u00c2\u00b7Ts, and then aminate (am-ih-\"nate\") and secrete it in a crucial metabolic cycle. Its receptors are agonized by kainate (kye-nate) and A\u00c2\u00b7M\u00c2\u00b7P\u00c2\u00b7A and are antagonized by PCP. Long-term potentiation improves synaptic plasticity by increasing the number of NMDA receptors for this compound. Deaminating this five-carbon compound forms alpha-K\u00c2\u00b7G in the malate-aspartate (mal-\"ate\"-asp-ar-\"tate\") shuttle. De\u00c2\u00b7carb\u00c2\u00b7oxy\u00c2\u00b7lating it forms GABA (GAB-uh), which has the opposite effect on target neurons. For 10 points, what major excitatory neurotransmitter\u00c2\u2014an amino acid with a carboxyl side chain\u00c2\u2014has a sodium salt found in Chinese food?", "answer": "glutamate [or E; or glutamic acid; or Glu; accept monosodium glutamate]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>glutamate</u></b> [or <b><u>E</u></b>; or <b><u>glutamic acid</u></b>; or <b><u>Glu</u></b>; accept <b><u>monosodium glutamate</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["glutamate", "glutamate", "E", "glutamic acid", "Glu", "monosodium glutamate"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A Herman Melville essay notes that this story's innocuous title is meant to deceive the \"super cial skimmer of pages,\" who fails to see that this story is \"deep as Dante.\" A character in this story mentions women poisoning their husbands' bedtime drinks as evidence that the whole earth is \"one stain of guilt, one mighty blood-spot.\" When its protagonist dies, \"no hopeful verse\" is carved upon his tombstone because \"his dying hour was gloom.\" While traveling with a man whose black staff resembles a living snake, the title character of this story meets Goody Cloyse and  nds his wife's pink ribbon hanging from a tree branch. The title character and his wife, Faith, are inducted into a Satanic cult in a forest clearing at the climax of, for 10 points, what short story by Nathaniel Hawthorne?", "answer": "Young Goodman Brown\"", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Young Goodman Brown\"</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Young Goodman Brown\"", "Young Goodman Brown\""], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An alkylation reactor reacts these compounds with iso\u00c2\u00b7butane and strong acid. The Dewar\u00c2\u2013Chatt\u00c2\u2013Duncanson model explains how these compounds act as ligands. Aldehydes are synthesized industrially by carbonylating these compounds. Dis\u00c2\u00b7proportionation during petroleum cracking makes equi\u00c2\u00b7molar hydrogen gas and these compounds as a byproduct. Carbenes add to these compounds to make cyclo\u00c2\u00b7propanes. The simplest Diels\u00c2\u2013Alder reaction uses one of these compounds as the dieno\u00c2\u00b7phile (\"die\"-EE-no-\"file\"). Ziegler\u00c2\u2013Natta catalysts polymerize these compounds. Markovnikov addition of water to these compounds gives an alcohol. Halogens add to them in the canonical test for un\u00c2\u00b7saturation. For 10 points, name these hydrocarbons with a carbon\u00c2\u2013carbon double bond.", "answer": "alkenes [or ole\u0620ns; or polyalkenes; or polyole\u0620ns; prompt on \"hydrocarbons\" before \"hydrocarbons\"]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>alkenes</u></b> [or <b><u>ole\u0620ns</u></b>; or <b><u>polyalkenes</u></b>; or <b><u>polyole\u0620ns</u></b>; prompt on <u>hydrocarbons\"</u> before \"hydrocarbons]", "acceptable": ["alkenes", "alkenes", "ole\u0620ns", "polyalkenes", "polyole\u0620ns"], "promptable": ["hydrocarbons\""], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One side in this war signed a free-trade agreement with Morocco negotiated by the so-called \"rabbi pirate\" Samuel Pallache (pah-LAHSH). Francis, Duke of Anjou, was given sovereignty over one side in this war but was forced out after his troops were massacred by the citizens of a key city; despite Federigo Giambelli's (jahm-\"BELLY's\") use of \"hellburners\" to destroy a pontoon bridge, that city surrendered to Alessandro Farnese (far-NAY-zay), Duke of Parma, during this war. The  rst assassination of a head of state by handgun was carried out by Balthasar Ge\u0301rard during this war. The Twelve Years' Truce interrupted this war, which was initiated by a faction that was joined by the Sea Beggars and Maurice of Nassau and formed by William the Silent. For 10 points, what long revolt resulted in Utrecht and Holland breaking from Habsburg Spain?", "answer": "Eighty Years' War [or Dutch War of Independence; accept Dutch Revolt; accept answers mentioning a war in which the Netherlands or Holland acquired independence from Spain; prompt on \"Dutch War\" or similar answers]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Eighty Years' War</u></b> [or <b><u>Dutch War of Independence</u></b>; accept <b><u>Dutch Revolt</u></b>; accept <b><u>answers mentioning a war in which the Netherlands</u></b> or <b><u>Holland acquired independence from Spain</u></b>; prompt on <u>Dutch War</u> or <u>similar answers</u>]", "acceptable": ["Eighty Years' War", "Eighty Years' War", "Dutch War of Independence", "Dutch Revolt", "answers mentioning a war in which the Netherlands", "Holland acquired independence from Spain"], "promptable": ["Dutch War", "similar answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An unresolved C-sharp dominant 7 chord, which ends the  rst song of one of this composer's cycles, has an ambiguous A-major or F-sharp-minor tonality. This man, who was an in&amp;uence on Hugo Wolf (VULF), included \"Mondnacht\" (MOND-nahkt) and \"In der Fremde\" (FREM-deh) in his Opus 39 song cycle based on twelve Joseph Freiherr von Eichendorff poems. This man wrote over 120 songs during his Liederjahr (LEE-dehr-yar), or \"Year of Song,\" including a cycle about doomed love based on 16 Heinrich Heine (\"HI\"-neh) poems. He promoted a young Johannes Brahms in his essay \"New Paths\" for his New Journal of Music. This composer of Dichterliebe (DIK-ter-lee-beh) included the piece \"Tra\u0308umerei\" (TROY-meh-\"rye\") in his Scenes from Childhood. For 10 points, name this Romantic composer of the Rhenish Symphony who married the pianist Clara Wieck (VEEK).", "answer": "Robert Schumann [accept Robert Alexander Schumann", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Robert Schumann [accept Robert Alexander <b><u>Schumann</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Robert Schumann [accept Robert Alexander Schumann", "Schumann"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A piece of an object used for this activity was used to heal the eye of a hawk, in whose stomach were a snake, a toad, and a louse that all carried the same message. A0er being defeated in this activity, two participants were forced to  ll four baskets up with &amp;owers, which was accomplished with the help of cutting ants. As a rabbit distracted gods engaged in this activity, one of their opponents retrieved his own decapitated head that had been lost at the House of Bats. This activity aroused the anger of the gods of the underworld because it made too much noise. In the Popol Vuh, the Hero Twins avenge their father and uncle by defeating the Lords of Xibalba (shee-\"BALL\"-bah) in this activity. For 10 points, what ritual sport using a round rubber object was played in Mesoamerica?", "answer": "Mesoamerican ballgame [or Mayan ballgame; or pohatok; or pitz; or ullamaliztli; accept answers mentioning a ball]", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Mesoamerican ballgame</u></b> [or <b><u>Mayan ballgame</u></b>; or <b><u>pohatok</u></b>; or <b><u>pitz</u></b>; or <b><u>ullamaliztli</u></b>; accept <b><u>answers mentioning a ball</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Mesoamerican ballgame", "Mesoamerican ballgame", "Mayan ballgame", "pohatok", "pitz", "ullamaliztli", "answers mentioning a ball"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "During this decade, a court set out the modern concept of negligence in Donoghue v. Stevenson, in which the remains of a snail were discovered in a bottle of ginger beer. A0er Palmer's shipyard went out of business in this decade, Ellen Wilkinson joined a 300-mile hunger march from Jarrow to London. Early in this decade, Britain was forced off the gold standard after naval pay cuts provoked the Invergordon mutiny. This decade's  rst general election was a massive defeat for the Labour Party after it expelled Ramsay MacDonald. This decade included both Edward VIII's (\"the eighth's\") abdication and Neville Chamberlain's claim that the Munich Agreement achieved \"peace for our time.\" For 10 points, name this decade dominated in the U.K. by the Great Depression.", "answer": "1930s [prompt on \"the thirties\"]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>1930s</u></b> [prompt on the <u>thirties</u>]", "acceptable": ["1930s", "1930s"], "promptable": ["thirties"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man created a character who has a one-legged father and a one-eyed mother, steals a copy of Animals and Plants of the European Coastal Region, and becomes obsessed with seaweed. He concluded a novel with a drawing of a rectangle and the question \"what's outside the window?\" A former Black Panther who wrote the cookbook Eating Ribs with Barry Seaman appears in a book by this man in which a journalist is sent to cover a boxing match. In one of his books, Arturo and Octavio take a Ford Impala into the desert in search of a \"visceral realist\" poet. He also created four critics who, while seeking the writer Benno von Archimboldi, travel to Santa Teresa, where many women have been murdered. For 10 points, what Chilean author wrote The Savage Detectives and 2666 (\"twenty six sixty six\")?", "answer": "Roberto Bolan\u0303o (boh-LAHN-yoh) [or Roberto Bolan\u0303o A\u0301valos]", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Roberto Bolan\u0303o</u></b> [or <b><u>Roberto Bolan\u0303o A\u0301valos</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Roberto Bolan\u0303o", "Roberto Bolan\u0303o", "Roberto Bolan\u0303o A\u0301valos"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "boh-LAHN-yoh"}, {"question": "When this term is \"materialized,\" it refers to the results of a database query. The S\u00c2\u00b7Q\u00c2\u00b7L command \"CREATE [this term] foo, \"AS\" (\"as\") query\" creates a virtual table named \"foo\" for the results of a query. Window coordinates transform into coordinates named for this term and \"port\" to get the rectangular area of the device where an image appears. It names the output representation in a so0ware design pattern for user interfaces named \"model, [this term], controller.\" In 3D graphics, objects are culled outside of the frustum named for this term, which is the space seen by the camera. In a  rst-person game, the angle subtended by the visible extent of the world is called the \" eld of\" this term. For 10 points, what term in web analytics is distinct from a \"hit\" and refers to a visitor's access of a webpage?", "answer": "view [or viewing; accept materialized view or view foo or viewport or model, view, controller or viewing frustum or  eld of view or pageview; prompt on \"vision\"]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>view</u></b> [or <b><u>viewing</u></b>; accept <b><u>materialized view</u></b> or <b><u>view foo</u></b> or <b><u>viewport</u></b> or <b><u>model, view, controller</u></b> or <b><u>viewing frustum</u></b> or <b><u>eld of view</u></b> or <b><u>pageview</u></b>; prompt on <u>vision</u>]", "acceptable": ["view", "view", "viewing", "materialized view", "view foo", "viewport", "model, view, controller", "viewing frustum", "eld of view", "pageview"], "promptable": ["vision"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Before a front vowel, the Proto-Greek labiovelar \"k\u00c2\u00b7w\" became the sound represented by this letter. Alfred Tarski's \"convention\" named for this letter says that \"sentence S in the object language is true if and only if it is true in the meta language.\" This letter denotes the empty category in the position out of which a \"w\u00c2\u00b7h\"-word moved. The voiceless sound represented by this letter debuccalizes (dee-\"BOOK\"-ah-ly-zes) to a glottal stop before a consonant in American English and between vowels in Cockney. This letter is a Latin suf x denoting the third-person singular present tense. This letter names the informal honori c in Indo-European languages, as distinguished from \"V.\" It is the voiceless alveolar (al-vee-OH-lar) stop in I\u00c2\u00b7P\u00c2\u00b7A, and its voiced counterpart is \"d.\" For 10 points, name this letter that is aspirated in the word \"time.\"", "answer": "T [accept Convention T or T-sentence or T\u00c2\u2013V distinction]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>T</u></b> [accept <b><u>Convention T</u></b> or <b><u>T-sentence</u></b> or <b><u>T\u00c2\u2013V distinction</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["T", "T", "Convention T", "T-sentence", "T\u00c2\u2013V distinction"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A poem about this event asks \"can you then impute a sinful deed to babes who on their mothers' bosoms bleed?\" and states \"one day everything will be well, that is our hope.\" This event inspires the killing of two men who refused to eat bacon and a Biscayan who had married his godmother. During this event, a man claims that a bay was created so that an Anabaptist could drown in it. A0er this event, a syphilitic, one-eyed character who survived it is apparently hanged during an auto-da-fe\u0301 on the orders of the grand inquisitor. This historical event leads the protagonist of a novella to question the idea that \"this is the best of all possible worlds,\" a theory of his tutor, Pangloss. For 10 points, name this disaster depicted in Candide that severely damaged an Iberian city.", "answer": "1755 Lisbon earthquake [or the Lisbon disaster; prompt on \"earthquake (in Candide)\"]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>1755 Lisbon earthquake</u></b> [or the <b><u>Lisbon disaster</u></b>; prompt on <u>earthquake (in Candide)</u>]", "acceptable": ["1755 Lisbon earthquake", "1755 Lisbon earthquake", "Lisbon disaster"], "promptable": ["earthquake (in Candide)"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Several photographs of this smiling person feature in a photorealistic \"vanitas\" still life by Audrey Flack. Dorothy Podber used a revolver to shoot a hole in a stack of four paintings of this person. A paste-up by Richard Hamilton consisting of crossed-out negatives of this person is titled \"my\" this person. Another painting features a small image of this person at the center of a six-foot-tall canvas covered in metallic gold paint. This person's face is depicted in 25 colorful images and 25 black-and-white images composing a 1962 artwork; like similar pieces featuring Jackie Kennedy and Mao Zedong, that silkscreen \"diptych\" depicting this woman was made in \"The Factory.\" For 10 points, name this actress whose image was repeatedly reproduced by Andy Warhol after her 1962 suicide.", "answer": "Marilyn Monroe [accept either underlined portion; or Norma Jeane Baker; or Norma Jean Mortenson; accept My Marilyn or Marilyn Diptych]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Marilyn <b><u>Monroe</u></b> [accept <b><u>either underlined portion</u></b>; or <b><u>Norma Jeane Baker</u></b>; or <b><u>Norma Jean Mortenson</u></b>; accept <b><u>My Marilyn</u></b> or <b><u>Marilyn Diptych</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Marilyn Monroe", "Monroe", "either underlined portion", "Norma Jeane Baker", "Norma Jean Mortenson", "My Marilyn", "Marilyn Diptych"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Bose\u00c2\u2013Einstein condensates can be described by a macroscopic version of this quantity equal to the root of the density distribution times a spatially varying phase factor. The anti-symmetrizer of this quantity can yield a determinant of many of these quantities. This quantity is assumed to be exponential with a slowly varying phase and amplitude compared to the de Broglie (de BROY-yeh) wavelength in the W\u00c2\u00b7K\u00c2\u00b7B approximation. The squared magnitude of this quantity gives the probability density, which is normalized to one when integrated. The Hamiltonian acting on this quantity equals an energy eigenvalue multiplied by this quantity in the time-independent Schro\u0308dinger equation. For 10 points, name this quantity, symbolized psi (\"sigh\"), that describes the quantum state of a particle.", "answer": "wavefunctions", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>wavefunctions</u></b>", "acceptable": ["wavefunctions", "wavefunctions"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This thinker's formulation of the problem of evil includes the metaphor of an architect whose design for a house subjects its residents to \"noise, confusion, fatigue, [and] darkness.\" He proposed that people understand necessary connections because of the \"constant conjugation\" of cause and effect through time. This thinker put forth metaphors of \"vegetation\" and \"generation\" as alternatives to analogizing the universe to a machine in a work in which Philo (\"FIE-low\") refutes the design argument made by Cleanthes (klee-ANN-theez). In another of his books, he distinguished between impressions and ideas by using the example of a man who has experienced all colors except for a \"missing shade of blue.\" For 10 points, who wrote Dialogues Concerning Natural Religion and An Enquiry Concerning Human Understanding?", "answer": "David Hume", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "David <b><u>Hume</u></b>", "acceptable": ["David Hume", "Hume"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This leader faced scandal when his mistress, B-movie actress Dovie Beams, played their sex tape during a press conference. Mutinying soldiers in training for Operation Merdeka, a secret invasion planned by this leader, were killed in the Jabidah massacre. This leader gave power to a group of cronies called the \"Rolex 12\" during a period intended to create a \"New Society.\" This leader called a snap election after coming under  re in Cardinal Jaime Sin's (\"HIGH-may SEEN's\") radio broadcasts, which accused him of ordering the assassination of his chief rival, a man named Benigno (beh-NEEG-noh), at an airport. The People Power revolution overthrew this leader in favor of Corazon Aquino (ah-KEE-noh). A prominent purchaser of footwear named Imelda was the wife of, for 10 points, what longtime dictator of the Philippines?", "answer": "Ferdinand Marcos [or Ferdinand Emmanuel Edralin Marcos Sr.]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "Ferdinand <b><u>Marcos</u></b> [or <b><u>Ferdinand Emmanuel Edralin Marcos Sr.</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Ferdinand Marcos", "Marcos", "Ferdinand Emmanuel Edralin Marcos Sr."], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Terry Gilliam's Brazil pays homage to this  lm sequence as Sam and Tuttle escape from the Ministry, replacing a key object from this scene with a vacuum cleaner. At its end, three separate shots of lion statues create the illusion that the lions are rising in response to the action of this sequence, which begins after the caption \"suddenly . . .\" interrupts a shot of a waving crowd that includes a legless man. The train station shootout from Brian de Palma's The Untouchables draws from this scene, which uses montage to intercut close-ups of a screaming, bleeding woman wearing shattered glasses with shots of a rolling baby carriage. For 10 points, what sequence from Sergei Eisenstein's Battleship Potemkin shows soldiers massacring a crowd &amp;eeing down a namesake structure?", "answer": "Odessa steps scene [or the steps scene from Battleship Potemkin; accept answers mentioning staircase or stairs in place of \"steps\"; accept steps or stairs scene a0er \"Battleship\"; prompt on partial answers]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Odessa steps scene</u></b> [or the <b><u>steps scene from Battleship Potemkin</u></b>; accept <b><u>answers mentioning staircase</u></b> or <b><u>stairs</u></b> in place of \"steps; accept <b><u>steps</u></b> or <b><u>stairs scene a0er \"Battleship</u></b>; prompt on <u>partial answers</u>]", "acceptable": ["Odessa steps scene", "Odessa steps scene", "steps scene from Battleship Potemkin", "answers mentioning staircase", "stairs", "steps", "stairs scene a0er \"Battleship"], "promptable": ["partial answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a poem addressed to this man, the speaker sees himself \"as one who sits ashore and longs . . . to visit dolphin-coral in deep seas\"; that sonnet to this man ends by invoking \"Dian (dy-ANN), Queen of Earth, and Heaven, and Hell\" and opens with the speaker \"standing aloof in giant ignorance.\" In another sonnet, this \"deep-brow'd\" man is called a ruler of a \"wide expanse,\" unlike the \"many goodly states and kingdoms\" that the speaker has seen; that poem's speaker recalls feeling, upon reading works originally by this man, like \"some watcher of the skies when a new planet swims into his ken\" or \"stout Cortez when with eagle eyes he star'd at the Paci c\" from \"a peak in Darien.\" For 10 points, name this subject of a John Keats sonnet praising George Chapman's translation of this man's Iliad.", "answer": "Homer [or Homeros]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Homer</u></b> [or <b><u>Homeros</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Homer", "Homer", "Homeros"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a namesake text, this man tells the story of a boy sent to Egypt to retrieve a pearl from a serpent who forgets about the pearl and his royal birth until he receives a letter from home; besides containing the Hymn of the Pearl, that text describes how Jesus sold this man as a slave to Abbanes (ah-BAH-neez), a merchant sent by King Gundaphorus (gun-dah-FOR-us). During the Last Supper, Jesus told this man that \"I am the way, and the truth, and the life.\" Jesus told this founder of the Seven and a Half Churches that \"blessed are those who have not seen and yet have believed.\" This apostle, who founded a namesake Christian community in India, exclaimed \"my Lord and my God!\" after Jesus came to him in person and showed him his wounds. For 10 points, name this apostle who declared his doubt about Jesus's resurrection.", "answer": "Saint Thomas the Apostle [or Thomas Didymus; accept Gospel of Thomas or Gospel According to Thomas or Book of Thomas]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Saint Thomas the Apostle</u></b> [or <b><u>Thomas Didymus</u></b>; accept <b><u>Gospel of Thomas</u></b> or <b><u>Gospel According to Thomas</u></b> or <b><u>Book of Thomas</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Saint Thomas the Apostle", "Saint Thomas the Apostle", "Thomas Didymus", "Gospel of Thomas", "Gospel According to Thomas", "Book of Thomas"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this play, a student exits with the sarcastic line \"goodnight, Prometheus,\" prompting another character to speculate that there's \"no such thing\" as \"Prometheus.\" A character in this play, who o0en waters a \"feeble little plant\" on her windowsill, receives a gardening hat and tools as a gi0. In this play, a character dances and yells \"OCOMOGOSIAY!\" (oh-koh-moh-goh-\"SIGH\"-ay) while wearing a colorful dress gi0ed to her by a man who calls her \"Alaiyo.\" At this play's climax, Bobo reveals that Willie has run off with money intended to open a liquor store. In this play, Karl Lindner's offer to buy back a house is rebuffed, and Walter and Ruth's family prepare to move into Clybourne Park, a white neighborhood. For 10 points, name this play featuring the Younger family, written by Lorraine Hansberry.", "answer": "A Raisin in the Sun", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "A <b><u>Raisin in the Sun</u></b>", "acceptable": ["A Raisin in the Sun", "Raisin in the Sun"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}